will come the looters.
And then the troublemakers.
And I will be unable
to protect you.
Unless?
Unless I am your husband.
Unless I am king.
I would hate to see anything
unfortunate befall you...
Or your son in such
rudderless times as these.
It is time to make
your choice, Penelope.
Before someone makes it for you.
Alkimos, get some beeswax.
Focus repairs on
the prow of the ship.
That storm really took
a bite out of our hide.
But we need the ship
to have her speed back.
Yes, my king.
The sea herself added another
day and a half to our journey
that we do not have to spare.
The woes of my
heart upon this sea.
What storm do you
think was worse?
The one we just sailed through,
or the one that is on your brow?
The storm to come.
The journey ahead.
The journey home.
Yes.
Polites, is I must get home
no matter what the cost.
I must.
I wonder if the costs
already paid.
No, Polites...
The costs were paid
both here and back in Troy.
With flesh and blood.
And this.
This is our reward, is it?
More hardship.
More storms.
Rough seas.
I cannot control the fates.
Nor the seas.
You forget that
I’ve seen you
perform miracles
before, Odysseus.
Miracles even
the gods couldn’t choose.
If this was my kingdom, yes.
But this is not my kingdom.
Back home in my kingdom--
By the gods of the sea!
The sea has teeth!
By the gods!
Charybdis!
It’s another one of Poseidon’s
weapons of vengeance.
You didn’t stop Poseidon.
You just made him more angry.
Alkimos, come steer.
Steer us around
the outside of it.
My king, the repairs
aren’t finished yet.
Without them, we won’t
be able to make that turn.
It will be almost impossible.
I will make that turn.
I will.
The sea!
It has swallowed so many,
but I had no idea
it had a mouth!
My king, the winds!
We’re losing speed!
Odysseus, what do we do?
We will not let it
dissuade us off our course.
Push, Alkimos!
Push, Polites!
Push!
We will ride the wind
and the waves to freedom!
Aye, my king!
Odysseus!
Look!
By the gods!
It follows!
Use the gift, son of Laertes!
The gift!
The gift the goddess
gave to you!
If it can help us, use it!
Soon, loyal Polites!
Use it now!
I will not let
Poseidon’s pet beat us.
He will not have the glory of
knowing I took the easy way out.
Move!
He is right.
You should use it.
It is too early in the game
for you to die, Odysseus.
Your pride will be your ruin.
You cannot win
this without help.
I can beat this beast on my own.
I do not need
your help, goddess.
I will get home in
spite of you...
and all the gods!
I will waste no
more breath on you.
Not when it can be used
for another purpose.
My king...
Who the hell is it
you’re talking to back there?
I will beat this beast
without your help, goddess.
The whirlpool!
It’s coming!
Better hold on to something.
Hold on, men.
It’s not just any whirlpool.
It’s a creature of Poseidon.
And if it’s hungry,
we must feed it.
We must feed it
until its belly is full.
Until it chokes!
Come on!
What do you mean feed it?
Feed it with what?
Quick!
Or we’ve already lost.
Yes, what the storm
has taken from us.
Grab the ropes.
Anything, planks, barrels.
Grab anything you can.
Absolute madness.
You went mad, old man.
Feed this beast.
Fill its belly.
And if not...
I will choke it myself
with my own body.
Looks like the sea must eat.
The fishing traps.
Yes, the provisions. Now!
The fishing traps?
What are we going to eat?
We don’t need them.
We’ll be home in two days.
Or we’ll be dead
trying to protect it.
Choke on it!
Choke on all of it!
It’s working!
Now what we need is distance.
Move!
Hear me, gods!
I am strong enough
to fight my own battles.
Damn you! Damn you!
Gods.
Please, please help us.
Father...
Father, why have
you abandoned us?
Odysseus is alive.
Who... who are you?
Save your breath, child.
Do not fear me.
How have you appeared like that?
Is this some magician’s trick?
A phantasm?
Please do not vex me, spirit!
Athena hears your prayers.
And you must hear my words.
Your father has
not abandoned you.
And neither have the gods.
I am doing all that I can.
Never before have I
seen a man fight for his home
so boldly as
your father does in war.
He honors me.
And for that, I am
doing all that I can.
But now, my child,
I must ask the same of you.
You must protect
your father’s house
at all costs, from
within and from without.
You must be prepared
to fight in war, yes.
But you must also be careful,
watchful, and cunning.
It is time for boys
to become men.
I see Odysseus in you.
Perhaps it will be enough.
Yes.
Be vigilant, Telemachus.
You will know it when
the moment comes.
And then you
will strike...
for your mother,
for your father, and for me.
A toast, then.
A toast to our health,
and in gratitude to
my most gracious hosts.
Who, if I might
speak freely,
deserve a king who would
protect them at home,
and not seek glory elsewhere.
And I most certainly
could be that king.
A kingdom so fine
deserves a ruler
who would never
think to abandon it.
This is the king’s house.
Odysseus’s house.
My father’s house.
Ah.
And where exactly is
your father, Telemachus?
I don’t see him.
All I see instead
is a home deserted,
a kingdom undefended,
vulnerable,
and of the king
himself some stories.
The poets are talking
out on the street.
Some say he’s lost at sea.
Others, that he dallies
with Cersei herself.
And I myself have heard
nothing but stories of
monsters and treasure
and violence
and such bloodshed.
Whatever stories you’ve heard,
you should know this:
while my father is gone
and in his absence,
I am bound to
defend what is his.
Well, if it’s a fight
you’re looking for, boy.
Honorable Antinous.
Strong words do harm
to the digestion.
And violence is an ill
guest in this house or any.
Please.
Of course, my lady.
Of course.
But I wouldn’t need to
be a guest if my queen
would take this suitor
to be her husband.
I fear I cannot remarry.
What?
I cannot remarry
until I finish this cloak
I’ve been
making for my son.
It is only custom and proper.
A parting gift for my
only flesh and blood.
Before my duties as queen
to my new king
fill my days and my hand.
Indeed.
Now far be it from me
to rush propriety.
And I surely look forward
to viewing the finished product.
Must the entire sea move
against Odysseus, Lord Poseidon?
Behavior from such a god
seems small and petty.
This isn’t petty.
This is revenge!
For my son, for what
Odysseus did to my son.
Your son, Lord Poseidon, was
harming and murdering innocents.
Perhaps he will
think twice next time.
Enjoy your pet hero
while you can, Athena.
With your gifts.
Your meddling matters not.
Odysseus will not
leave my ocean alive.
Polites, how is she?
Is she patched up yet?
She’s looking pretty good.
Pretty good,
a little bit more...
beeswax and
she’ll be good to go.
Good, good.
Set a course for home, Alkimos.
Yes, my king.
For home, and for our rewards.
Gold.
Yes, yes, indeed, Polites.
Indeed.
And just on that,
by the way, I’ve been meaning
to tell you, meaning
to ask about...
Odysseus!
A monster!
The Scylla!
Poseidon’s lap dog!
Alkimos, no!
Odysseus!
What do we do?
We try to outrun it.
The wind...
The wind will guide us.
Yes... Yes, faster!
Faster!
No!
No! There’s not enough wind
at our back!
Not enough wind to fight!
Only the monster at our heels!
Damn my pride!
Athena! Athena!
I’m asking for help!
Another gift, then?
Goddess!
We need weapons!
Ask, and it will be yours.
Strategy. And sight.
Sight.
That will be my second gift.
To see what is
right in front of you.
What is right in front of me?
What? What does that mean?
My ship.
You ask for a weapon,
and yet you sail one.
Yes.
Why didn’t I see that before?
The ship is a weapon.
Sometimes you are so
worried about what is ahead,
that you fail to see what
is directly in front of you.
Take heed, Odysseus.
You will defeat the
monsters that surround you.
Odysseus?
Odysseus, you’re steering us...
You steer us right towards it!
Right towards the
jaws of the beast!
Not the jaws!
It’s belly!
We’ll run it through
with the prow!
The ship will be our sword!
Yes! Yes!
Odysseus, it’s
not going to work!
We’ve got to turn her
around or we’re done for!
The current is too strong!
It’s not working!
She’s going to eat us alive!
Hold fast, Polites!
We need momentum!
I’m trying!
That’s the only
belly-full you’ll get today!
Yes, Odysseus!
Yes!
Come on, Telemachus.
You must be ready to fight!
Or we’ll lose everything.
Come home, father.
Quickly.
The cloak you make
for me is nearly finished.
And there are unwanted
guests in your house.
About the cloak...
Alas, my son.
I fear there is still
so much work to be done.
This cloak may take
many days to finish.
You’re undoing what you’ve done.
If only I could.
Mother, you’ve
done nothing wrong.
It’s just...
What?
Undoing the cloak every night.
Sometimes clever
is better than good.
I just pray it buys
us the time he needs.
And if it doesn’t, then
I will be ready to fight.
No one is taking
this kingdom from us.
No one.
And I will be ready to fight.
Odysseus?
Odysseus.
Treacherous waters ahead.
♪ Come to us
That’s treacherous
waters indeed.
It means we’re getting
close to land now.
Huh.
That’s the first good
thing I’ve heard all day.
We must stay clear
of those rocks.
And I have less
than a day before...
Yeah, before someone claims
what is rightfully yours.
I know, my king.
I know.
I am no king here.
There is only one
king in the ocean.
And I hold no favor
with him now.
♪ Come to us
Odysseus...
Can you hear that?
- Music?
- No.
No, not the songs...
of the sirens, no.
♪ Come to us
No.
Polites, no. No!
Protect yourself!
No!
- Sirens.
- Not the sirens!
They call to me.
No!
Cover your ears!
Protect yourself, Polites!
They speak to me.
Cover your ears!
Protect yourself!
They want me to get my reward.
Rewards for a good man.
No. No!
They speak to me.
I hear the song.
It’s in my head!
They speak to me.
Telemachus is the
real problem here.
The woman?
I can handle.
But the boy?
Any loyal dog would
struggle obeying a new master.